{
  "chunks": [
    {
      "text": "Tesla Inc TSLA QQ 16 Jul 2025 21:42, UTC Last Price Fair Value Estimate PriceFVE Market Cap Economic MoatT M Equity Style Box Uncertainty Capital Allocation ESG Risk Rating Assessment1 321.67 USD 250.00 USD 1.29 1.04 USD Tril Narrow 3 Large Growth Very High Exemplary ;;;;; 16 Jul 2025 30 Jan 2025 05:50, UTC 16 Jul 2025 4 Jun 2025 05:00, UTC Price vs. Fair Value Last Close: 321.67 334 Fair Value: 250.00 30 Jan 2025 05:50, UTC 254 Overvalued Undervalued 174 94 14 2020 2021 2022 2023 2024 YTD Analysis 2.31 1.55 0.49 1.18 1.92 1.29 PriceFair Value 743.44 49.76 -65.03 101.72 62.52 -20.35 Total Return Morningstar Rating Total Return as of 16 Jul 2025. Last Close as of 16 Jul 2025. Fair Value as of 30 Jan 2025 05:50, UTC. Contents Tesla: Shares Fall as US Law Set To Eliminate EV Tax Credits Analyst Note (7 Jul 2025) Business Description Early; Musk Plans to Start New Party Business Strategy Outlook (23 Apr 2025) Bulls Say Bears Say (23 Apr 2025) Analyst Note Seth Goldstein, CFA, Senior Equity Analyst, 7 Jul 2025 Economic Moat (23 Apr 2025) Fair Value and Profit Drivers (23 Apr 2025) Electric vehicle tax credits worth up to 7,500 will now expire after September, seven years and three Risk and Uncertainty (23 Apr 2025) months early, thanks to the Republican spending bill signed into law July 4. Tesla CEO Elon Musk also Capital Allocation (11 Mar 2025) said he plans to create a new political party. Tesla shares were down 7 in premarket trading. Analyst Notes Archive Financials Why it matters: The elimination of the EV tax credits will likely result in lower sales volumes for Tesla ESG Risk after the credits expire, especially in 2026. The decline is likely to be industrywide, as we expect US EV Appendix sales to decline in 2026, similar to other countries following a subsidy cut. Research Methodology for Valuing Companies gMusk's plan to start a new political party could serve as a distraction from his role at Tesla. This could Important Disclosure lead to the delay of Tesla's goals, which include moving the new robotaxi from testing to full launch The conduct of Morningstar s analysts is governed by Code of EthicsCode of Conduct Policy, Personal Security Trading Policy (or an equivalent of), and and the production and sale of a new, more affordable vehicle. Investment Research Policy. For information regarding conflicts of interest, please visit: The bottom line: For now, we maintain our 250 fair value estimate. We view narrow-moat Tesla The primary analyst covering this company does not own its stock. shares as slightly overvalued, with the stock trading approximately 20 above our fair value estimate. 1The ESG Risk Rating Assessment is a representation of Sustainalytics ESG Risk Accordingly, we recommend investors wait for a larger pullback before considering an entry point. Rating. gFor Tesla, sales of the Model 3 and Model Y could be the most affected. While these models are priced in the lower end of the luxury market, we think many buyers in the affordable vehicle market paid up for these models after tax credits. gWe will wait to hear from management in the earnings call later this month before updating our Morningstar 2025. All Rights Reserved. Unless otherwise provided in a separate agreement, you may use this report only in the country in which its original distributor is based. The information, data, analyses and ?(cid:0) opinions presented herein do not constitute investment advice; are provided solely for informational purposes and therefore are not an offer to buy or sell a security; and are not warranted to be correct, complete or accurate. The opinions expressed are as of the date written and are subject to change without notice. Except as otherwise required by law, Morningstar shall not be responsible for any trading decisions, damages or other losses resulting from, or related to, the information, data, analyses or opinions or their use. The information contained herein is the proprietary property of Morningstar and may not be reproduced, in whole or in part, or used in any manner, without the prior written consent of Morningstar. Investment research is produced and issued by subsidiaries of Morningstar, Inc. including, but not limited to, Morningstar Research Services LLC, registered with and governed by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. To order reprints, call 1 . To license the research, call 1 . Please see important disclosures at the end of this report. Page 2 Morningstar Equity Analyst Report Report as of 17 Jul 2025 00:55, UTC Reporting Currency: USD Trading Currency: USD Exchange: NASDAQ - ALL MARKETS",
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Tesla Inc",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "321.67 USD 250.00 USD",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "30 Jan 2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025 4",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "05:00",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC Price",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Fair Value",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "321.67",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "334",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "250.00",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "30 Jan 2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "254",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "174",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "14 2020 2021 2022 2023 2024",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2.31 1.55",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "1.92 1.29",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "49.76",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "101.72",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Fair Value",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "30 Jan 2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Analyst Note",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "7",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Start New Party Business Strategy Outlook",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "23",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Bulls Say Bears Say",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "23",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Seth Goldstein",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "CFA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "7",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Fair Value",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Profit Drivers",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "23",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "up to 7,500",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "September",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "seven years",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "23",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "months early",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Republican",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "July 4",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Elon Musk",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Capital Allocation",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "11",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "7",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "EV",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla ESG Risk",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "2026",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2026",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Conduct Policy, Personal Security Trading Policy",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Investment Research Policy",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "250",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "approximately 20",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "1The",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Sustainalytics ESG Risk Accordingly",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "gFor Tesla",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "the Model 3 and Model Y",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        },
        {
          "text": "later this month",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar 2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar, Inc.",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar Research Services",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "LLC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Page 2 Morningstar Equity Analyst Report Report",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "17",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "00:55",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC Reporting Currency",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "USD Exchange",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "keywords": [
        "Shares",
        "full launch",
        "The decline",
        "narrow-moat Tesla",
        "conflicts",
        "gFor Tesla",
        "7 Jul 2025 Economic Moat",
        "The information",
        "Jun",
        "NASDAQ - ALL"
      ],
      "summary": "Tesla Inc TSLA QQ 16 Jul 2025 21:42, UTC Last Price Fair Value Estimate PriceFVE Market Cap Economic MoatT M Equity Style Box Uncertainty Capital Allocation ESG Risk Rating Assessment1 321.67 USD 250.00 USD 1.29 1.04 USD Tril Narrow 3 Large Growth Very High Exemplary ;;;;; 16 Jul 2025 30 Jan 2025 05:50, UTC 16 Jul 2025 4 Jun 2025 05:00, UTC Price vs. Fair Value Last Close: 321.67 334 Fair Value: 250.00 30 Jan 2025 05:50, UTC 254 Overvalued Undervalued 174 94 14 2020 2021 2022 2023 2024 YTD"
    },
    {
      "text": "Tesla Inc TSLA QQ 16 Jul 2025 21:42, UTC Last Price Fair Value Estimate PriceFVE Market Cap Economic MoatTM Equity Style Box Uncertainty Capital Allocation ESG Risk Rating Assessment1 321.67 USD 250.00 USD 1.29 1.04 USD Tril Narrow 3 Large Growth Very High Exemplary ;;;;; 16 Jul 2025 30 Jan 2025 05:50, UTC 16 Jul 2025 4 Jun 2025 05:00, UTC Sector Industry forecast. However, we estimate a fair value decrease of 5-10 from lower sales volumes. tConsumer Cyclical Auto Manufacturers Big picture: We will review our US EV forecast for sales to reach 25 of autos by 2030. We expect to Business Description reduce it following the early elimination of the tax credit subsidy. While we expect a large decline in Tesla is a vertically integrated battery electric vehicle 2026, EV sales should return to growth in 2027, consistent with subsidy cuts in other countries. automaker and developer of autonomous driving software. The company has multiple vehicles in its fleet, which include luxury and midsize sedans, crossover Business Strategy Outlook Seth Goldstein, CFA, Senior Equity Analyst, 23 Apr 2025 SUVs, a light truck, and a semi truck. Tesla also plans to Tesla is one of the largest battery electric vehicle automakers in the world. In less than a decade, the begin selling more affordable vehicles, a sports car, and firm went from a startup to a globally recognized luxury automaker with its Model S and Model X offer a robotaxi service. Global deliveries in 2024 were a little below 1.8 million vehicles. The company sells vehicles. Tesla competes in the entry-level luxury car and midsize crossover sport utility vehicle markets batteries for stationary storage for residential and with its Model 3 and Model Y vehicles. It also sells a light truck the Cybertruck and a semi truck. It commercial properties including utilities and solar plans to launch an affordable SUV, luxury sports car, and robotaxi in the future. panels and solar roofs for energy generation. Tesla also owns a fast-charging network. Tesla aims to retain its market leader status as EVs grow from a niche market to reaching mass consumer adoption. We forecast EVs will reach one in three autos sold globally by 2030. To meet growing demand, Tesla opened two new factories in 2022, increasing its production capacity. Tesla also invests around 4 of its sales in research and development, focusing on improving its market-leading technology and reducing manufacturing costs. For EVs to see mass adoption, long-range EVs need to reach cost parity with internal combustion engines across all vehicle categories. To reduce costs, Tesla focuses on automation and efficiency in its manufacturing process, such as reducing the total number of parts that need to be assembled in a vehicle. The company also designs some of its own batteries. Tesla's goal is to reduce costs by more than 50 over time. EVs also need readily available fast-chargers throughout a region to see mass-market adoption. Tesla continues to expand its supercharging network, which consists of fast chargers built along highways and in cities throughout the US, EU, and China. Tesla is attempting to take a larger share of its customers' auto-related spending, which includes selling autonomous driving software, insurance, and charging. The company also aims to launch a robotaxi service using its autonomous driving software. We expect autonomous vehicles, including Tesla's robotaxi service, to make up 50 of ride-hailing rides in the US and Canada by 2030 as robotaxis are cheaper than human drivers. It also sells solar panels and batteries to consumers and utilities. As the battery-based energy storage market expands, Tesla is well positioned to grow accordingly. Bulls Say Seth Goldstein, CFA, Senior Equity Analyst, 23 Apr 2025 uTesla has the potential to disrupt the automotive and power generation industries with its technology for EVs, AVs, batteries, and solar generation systems. uTesla will see higher profit margins as it reduces unit production costs over the next several years. Morningstar 2025. All Rights Reserved. Unless otherwise provided in a separate agreement, you may use this report only in the country in which its original distributor is based. The information, data, analyses and ?(cid:0) opinions presented herein do not constitute investment advice; are provided solely for informational purposes and therefore are not an offer to buy or sell a security; and are not warranted to be correct, complete or accurate. The opinions expressed are as of the date written and are subject to change without notice. Except as otherwise required by law, Morningstar shall not be responsible for any trading decisions, damages or other losses resulting from, or related to, the information, data, analyses or opinions or their use. The information contained herein is the proprietary property of Morningstar and may not be reproduced, in whole or in part, or used in any manner, without the prior written consent of Morningstar. Investment research is produced and issued by subsidiaries of Morningstar, Inc. including, but not limited to, Morningstar Research Services LLC, registered with and governed by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. To order reprints, call 1 . To license the research, call 1 . Please see important disclosures at the end of this report. Page 3 Morningstar Equity Analyst Report Report as of 17 Jul 2025 00:55, UTC Reporting Currency: USD Trading Currency: USD Exchange: NASDAQ - ALL MARKETS",
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Tesla Inc",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "321.67 USD 250.00 USD",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "30 Jan 2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025 4",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "05:00",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC Sector Industry",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "5",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "25",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2030",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Business Description",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2026",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "EV",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "2027",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Business Strategy Outlook Seth Goldstein",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CFA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "23",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "less than a decade",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Model S",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        },
        {
          "text": "Model X",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        },
        {
          "text": "2024",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "1.8 million",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Model 3 and Model Y",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        },
        {
          "text": "Cybertruck",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "one",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "three",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2030",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "around 4",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "more than 50",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "EU",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "50",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Canada",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2030",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CFA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "23",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "AVs",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        },
        {
          "text": "the next several years",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar 2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar, Inc.",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar Research Services",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "LLC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar Equity Analyst Report Report",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "17",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "00:55",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC Reporting Currency",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "USD Exchange",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "keywords": [
        "research",
        "its fleet",
        "mass-market adoption",
        "AVs",
        "The information",
        "Jun",
        "NASDAQ - ALL",
        "USD Exchange",
        "informational purposes",
        "a security"
      ],
      "summary": "Tesla Inc TSLA QQ 16 Jul 2025 21:42, UTC Last Price Fair Value Estimate PriceFVE Market Cap Economic MoatTM Equity Style Box Uncertainty Capital Allocation ESG Risk Rating Assessment1 321.67 USD 250.00 USD 1.29 1.04 USD Tril Narrow 3 Large Growth Very High Exemplary ;;;;; 16 Jul 2025 30 Jan 2025 05:50, UTC 16 Jul 2025 4 Jun 2025 05:00, UTC Sector Industry forecast."
    },
    {
      "text": "Tesla Inc TSLA QQ 16 Jul 2025 21:42, UTC Last Price Fair Value Estimate PriceFVE Market Cap Economic MoatTM Equity Style Box Uncertainty Capital Allocation ESG Risk Rating Assessment1 321.67 USD 250.00 USD 1.29 1.04 USD Tril Narrow 3 Large Growth Very High Exemplary ;;;;; 16 Jul 2025 30 Jan 2025 05:50, UTC 16 Jul 2025 4 Jun 2025 05:00, UTC Competitors Tesla Inc TSLA Ford Motor Co F Bayerische Motoren Werke AG BMW Volkswagen AG ...hne Stimmrecht VOW3 Last Close Fair Value Fair Value Fair Value 321.67 16.00 117.00 172.00 Uncertainty : High Uncertainty : High Uncertainty : Very High Fair Value 250.00 Last Close Last Close Uncertainty : Very High 11.24 85.06 Last Close 93.54 Analysis Security 1 Security 2 Security 3 Security 4 Economic Moat Narrow None None None Currency USD USD EUR EUR Fair Value 250.00 30 Jan 2025 05:50, UTC 16.00 11 Feb 2025 00:56, UTC 117.00 26 Nov 2024 19:25, UTC 172.00 24 Apr 2025 13:40, UTC 1-Star Price 437.50 24.80 181.35 301.00 5-Star Price 125.00 9.60 70.20 86.00 Assessment Overvalued 16 Jul 2025 Undervalued 16 Jul 2025 Undervalued 16 Jul 2025 Undervalued 16 Jul 2025 Morningstar Rating QQ16 Jul 2025 21:42, UTC QQQQ16 Jul 2025 21:28, UTC QQQQ16 Jul 2025 00:35, UTC QQQQ16 Jul 2025 00:55, UTC Analyst Seth Goldstein, Senior Equity Analyst David Whiston, Senior Equity Analyst Rella Suskin, Equity Analyst Rella Suskin, Equity Analyst Capital Allocation Exemplary Standard Standard Poor PriceFair Value 1.29 0.70 0.73 0.54 PriceSales 11.39 0.25 0.35 0.14 PriceBook 13.40 1.03 0.56 0.27 PriceEarning 161.20 7.77 7.53 3.76 Dividend Yield 0.00 6.48 5.06 6.80 Market Cap 1,036.08 Bil 44.70 Bil 52.56 Bil 45.18 Bil 52-Week Range 182.00 488.54 8.44 14.85 62.96 91.78 78.86 114.20 Investment Style Large Growth Mid Value Large Value Large Value uTesla's full self-driving software should generate growing profits in the coming years as the technology continues to improve, leading to a robotaxi service, increased adoption by Tesla drivers, and licensing from other auto manufacturers. Bears Say Seth Goldstein, CFA, Senior Equity Analyst, 23 Apr 2025 uTraditional automakers and new entrants are investing heavily in EV development, which will result in Tesla seeing a deceleration in sales growth and being forced to cut prices due to increased competition, eroding profit margins. uTesla's large investment into autonomous driving software will be value destructive as the robotaxi product will face delays and competition from Waymo, who already offers a robotaxi service. uTesla CEO Elon Musk's political activities will turn consumers away from buying a Tesla in key markets including the US and Europe, leading to lower sales and profits. Morningstar 2025. All Rights Reserved. Unless otherwise provided in a separate agreement, you may use this report only in the country in which its original distributor is based. The information, data, analyses and ?(cid:0) opinions presented herein do not constitute investment advice; are provided solely for informational purposes and therefore are not an offer to buy or sell a security; and are not warranted to be correct, complete or accurate. The opinions expressed are as of the date written and are subject to change without notice. Except as otherwise required by law, Morningstar shall not be responsible for any trading decisions, damages or other losses resulting from, or related to, the information, data, analyses or opinions or their use. The information contained herein is the proprietary property of Morningstar and may not be reproduced, in whole or in part, or used in any manner, without the prior written consent of Morningstar. Investment research is produced and issued by subsidiaries of Morningstar, Inc. including, but not limited to, Morningstar Research Services LLC, registered with and governed by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. To order reprints, call 1 . To license the research, call 1 . Please see important disclosures at the end of this report. Page 4 Morningstar Equity Analyst Report Report as of 17 Jul 2025 00:55, UTC Reporting Currency: USD Trading Currency: USD Exchange: NASDAQ - ALL MARKETS",
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Tesla Inc",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "321.67 USD 250.00 USD",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "30 Jan 2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025 4",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "05:00",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC Competitors Tesla Inc",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Ford Motor Co F Bayerische Motoren Werke AG",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Volkswagen AG",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Stimmrecht",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "117.00 172.00 Uncertainty : High Uncertainty : High Uncertainty : Very High Fair Value",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "85.06",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "93.54",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "30 Jan 2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "16.00",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "00:56",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "117.00",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "172.00 24 Apr",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC 1-Star",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "437.50",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "301.00 5-Star",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        },
        {
          "text": "125.00",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "70.20 86.00",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar Rating",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025 21:42",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Jul 2025 00:35",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Jul 2025",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "00:55",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Seth Goldstein",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "David Whiston",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Rella Suskin",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Rella Suskin",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "11.39 0.25",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "0.14",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "13.40",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "0.27",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "161.20",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "3.76",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "0.00",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "6.48",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "5.06 6.80",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "44.70",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "52.56",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "52-Week",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "488.54",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "62.96 91.78",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "78.86 114.20",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "the coming years",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Seth Goldstein",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "CFA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "23",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "EV",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "uTesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Waymo",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        },
        {
          "text": "Elon Musk's",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Europe",
          "label": "LOC"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar 2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar, Inc.",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar Research Services",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "LLC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Page 4",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar Equity Analyst Report Report",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "17",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "00:55",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC Reporting Currency",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "USD Exchange",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "keywords": [
        "licensing",
        "Feb",
        "The information",
        "Jun",
        "NASDAQ - ALL",
        "increased competition",
        "USD Exchange",
        "informational purposes",
        "a security",
        "Inc."
      ],
      "summary": "Tesla Inc TSLA QQ 16 Jul 2025 21:42, UTC Last Price Fair Value Estimate PriceFVE Market Cap Economic MoatTM Equity Style Box Uncertainty Capital Allocation ESG Risk Rating Assessment1 321.67 USD 250.00 USD 1.29 1.04 USD Tril Narrow 3 Large Growth Very High Exemplary ;;;;; 16 Jul 2025 30 Jan 2025 05:50, UTC 16 Jul 2025 4 Jun 2025 05:00, UTC Competitors Tesla Inc TSLA Ford Motor Co F Bayerische Motoren Werke AG BMW Volkswagen AG ...hne Stimmrecht VOW3"
    },
    {
      "text": "Tesla Inc TSLA QQ 16 Jul 2025 21:42, UTC Last Price Fair Value Estimate PriceFVE Market Cap Economic MoatTM Equity Style Box Uncertainty Capital Allocation ESG Risk Rating Assessment1 321.67 USD 250.00 USD 1.29 1.04 USD Tril Narrow 3 Large Growth Very High Exemplary ;;;;; 16 Jul 2025 30 Jan 2025 05:50, UTC 16 Jul 2025 4 Jun 2025 05:00, UTC Economic Moat Seth Goldstein, CFA, Senior Equity Analyst, 23 Apr 2025 We award Tesla a narrow moat rating. Tesla's moat stems from two of our five moat sources: intangible assets and cost advantage. The company's strong brand cachet as a luxury automaker commands premium pricing, while its EV manufacturing expertise allows the company to make its vehicles cheaper than its competitors. Intangible Assets Tesla's brand cachet is not likely to be impaired anytime soon as other automakers move into the battery electric vehicle space because we expect the company to keep innovating to stay ahead of startup and established competitors. The Model S Plaid, the most upgraded version of Tesla's luxury sedan, offers 390 miles of range, at the high end for electric vehicles. It does 0-60 mph in under 2 seconds and has 1,020 horsepower, putting the Model S Plaid in a rare class of performance among all autos, regardless of powertrain. By focusing on the luxury auto market first, Tesla was able to create tremendous media publicity for the company that reaches beyond its customers. This generated strong consumer demand for its subsequent vehicles at lower price points, such as the Model 3 and Model Y. As other new vehicles are launched, such as the affordable SUV, we expect the company's strong brand will continue to generate consumer demand. Tesla has a more high-tech vehicle with the ability to do drivetrain updates and other updates via Wi-Fi or a cellular connection, and customers do not have to visit a store for many service needs. Tesla will instead pick up the vehicle from home and often return it the same day, while providing a fully loaded loaner for no charge, or visit the customer's home or work and service the car there. This experience is much easier than many other automakers' service, which helps Tesla's brand equity. Further, this has been accomplished with little to no spending on advertising, which is rare for a consumer brand. This strong brand equity has carried over to Tesla's energy generation and storage business, where the company can charge a premium for its fully integrated solar panel, inverter, and home battery storage systems sold to consumers. Tesla's proprietary technology contributes to its intangible asset-driven competitive advantage. This form of intangible assets applies to EVs due to their innovative, highly engineered nature and because patents for EV technologies hold somewhat less value due to the ability of competitors to create alternatively designed, but ultimately similar, products. Since launching the Model S in 2012, Tesla has been the industry leader in electric vehicles, producing the best EVs on the market. The company invests nearly 6 of sales in RD to maintain its best-in-class range, which is well ahead of the competition on a miles per kilowatt-hour basis and continues to improve other vehicle specs such as power. Tesla is also investing heavily in its proprietary autonomous vehicle technology and building one of the world's largest supercomputers to train self-driving artificial intelligence. With RD spending in Morningstar 2025. All Rights Reserved. Unless otherwise provided in a separate agreement, you may use this report only in the country in which its original distributor is based. The information, data, analyses and ?(cid:0) opinions presented herein do not constitute investment advice; are provided solely for informational purposes and therefore are not an offer to buy or sell a security; and are not warranted to be correct, complete or accurate. The opinions expressed are as of the date written and are subject to change without notice. Except as otherwise required by law, Morningstar shall not be responsible for any trading decisions, damages or other losses resulting from, or related to, the information, data, analyses or opinions or their use. The information contained herein is the proprietary property of Morningstar and may not be reproduced, in whole or in part, or used in any manner, without the prior written consent of Morningstar. Investment research is produced and issued by subsidiaries of Morningstar, Inc. including, but not limited to, Morningstar Research Services LLC, registered with and governed by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. To order reprints, call 1 . To license the research, call 1 . Please see important disclosures at the end of this report. Page 5 Morningstar Equity Analyst Report Report as of 17 Jul 2025 00:55, UTC Reporting Currency: USD Trading Currency: USD Exchange: NASDAQ - ALL MARKETS",
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Tesla Inc",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "321.67 USD 250.00 USD",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "30 Jan 2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025 4",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "05:00",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "CFA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "23",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "two",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "five",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "EV",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "The Model S Plaid",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "390 miles",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "0-60 mph",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "under 2 seconds",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "1,020",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "the Model S Plaid",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "first",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "the Model 3",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        },
        {
          "text": "Model Y.",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Wi-Fi",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "the same day",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "EV",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "the Model S",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "2012",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "nearly 6",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "RD",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "a miles",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "RD",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar 2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar, Inc.",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar Research Services",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "LLC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "5",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar Equity Analyst Report Report",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "17",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "00:55",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC Reporting Currency",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "USD Exchange",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "keywords": [
        "kilowatt-hour basis",
        "updates",
        "all autos",
        "Jun",
        "Wi-Fi",
        "The information",
        "the ability",
        "NASDAQ - ALL",
        "USD Exchange",
        "informational purposes"
      ],
      "summary": "Tesla Inc TSLA QQ 16 Jul 2025 21:42, UTC Last Price Fair Value Estimate PriceFVE Market Cap Economic MoatTM Equity Style Box Uncertainty Capital Allocation ESG Risk Rating Assessment1 321.67 USD 250.00 USD 1.29 1.04 USD Tril Narrow 3 Large Growth Very High Exemplary ;;;;; 16 Jul 2025 30 Jan 2025 05:50, UTC 16 Jul 2025 4 Jun 2025 05:00, UTC Economic Moat Seth Goldstein, CFA, Senior Equity Analyst, 23 Apr 2025 We award Tesla a narrow moat rating."
    },
    {
      "text": "Tesla Inc TSLA QQ 16 Jul 2025 21:42, UTC Last Price Fair Value Estimate PriceFVE Market Cap Economic MoatTM Equity Style Box Uncertainty Capital Allocation ESG Risk Rating Assessment1 321.67 USD 250.00 USD 1.29 1.04 USD Tril Narrow 3 Large Growth Very High Exemplary ;;;;; 16 Jul 2025 30 Jan 2025 05:50, UTC 16 Jul 2025 4 Jun 2025 05:00, UTC line with its peers, we think Tesla will be able to maintain its proprietary technological advantage. Tesla will face increasing competition in the coming years. Automakers plan to electrify their fleets by adding EV versions of existing vehicles and creating new platforms. However, we see EVs becoming a greater proportion of auto sales, growing to 30 by 2030 from 3 in 2020, which will expand the market as EVs rapidly take share from internal combustion engine vehicles. As new models are introduced, Tesla's technological advantage and the strength of its brand will remain intact, which will allow the company to continue to charge a premium price for its EVs. Cost Advantage We think Tesla benefits from a cost advantage in electric vehicles production thanks to its manufacturing scale. Tesla's total vehicle volume has grown from just over 100,000 in 2017 to nearly 1.8 million deliveries in 2024. During the same period, the company's average cost of goods sold per vehicle has fallen over 55, from 84,000 to just over 35,000. While some of this is due to manufacturing a greater proportion of midsize cars and SUVs versus luxury autos, the majority of the COGS decline has come from the company's focus on reducing manufacturing costs due to scale. Legacy automakers are gradually transitioning to BEV production from internal combustion engines, but we expect they will be saddled with legacy ICE costs for a long time. Even as legacy automakers begin to produce more EVs, we expect Tesla will continue to have lower costs as it has outlined a plan to further reduce unit production costs over the next several years with a new manufacturing process. With Tesla's cost per vehicle set to fall, legacy automakers may take years to catch up to Tesla, if ever, as they won't want to build many new factories from scratch like Tesla is doing. We think Tesla's combination of intangible assets and cost advantage will persist in the future and allow the firm to generate excess returns on capital. We see the potential for Tesla to outearn its cost of capital over at least the next 20 years, which is the measurement we use for a wide moat rating. However, the second 10-year period carries significant uncertainty for both Tesla and the broader automotive industry, given the rapid advancement of autonomous vehicle technologies that could transform how consumers use vehicles. As such, we view a narrow moat rating, which assumes a 10- year excess return duration, as more appropriate. Fair Value and Profit DriversSeth Goldstein, CFA, Senior Equity Analyst, 23 Apr 2025 Our Tesla fair value estimate is 250. We use a weighted average cost of capital of just under 9. Our equity valuation adds back nonrecourse and nondilutive convertible debt. In 2025, we forecast deliveries will slightly fall versus the 1.79 million deliveries in 2024. We expect first half deliveries will be affected by the new Model Y not being solid in all markets, especially in the beginning of the year. However, we forecast a better second half of the year as the affordable vehicle is Morningstar 2025. All Rights Reserved. Unless otherwise provided in a separate agreement, you may use this report only in the country in which its original distributor is based. The information, data, analyses and ?(cid:0) opinions presented herein do not constitute investment advice; are provided solely for informational purposes and therefore are not an offer to buy or sell a security; and are not warranted to be correct, complete or accurate. The opinions expressed are as of the date written and are subject to change without notice. Except as otherwise required by law, Morningstar shall not be responsible for any trading decisions, damages or other losses resulting from, or related to, the information, data, analyses or opinions or their use. The information contained herein is the proprietary property of Morningstar and may not be reproduced, in whole or in part, or used in any manner, without the prior written consent of Morningstar. Investment research is produced and issued by subsidiaries of Morningstar, Inc. including, but not limited to, Morningstar Research Services LLC, registered with and governed by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. To order reprints, call 1 . To license the research, call 1 . Please see important disclosures at the end of this report. Page 6 Morningstar Equity Analyst Report Report as of 17 Jul 2025 00:55, UTC Reporting Currency: USD Trading Currency: USD Exchange: NASDAQ - ALL MARKETS",
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Tesla Inc",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "321.67 USD 250.00 USD",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "30 Jan 2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025 4",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "05:00",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "the coming years",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "EV",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "30",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2030",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2020",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "just over 100,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2017",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "nearly 1.8 million",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2024",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "55",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "84,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "just over 35,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "COGS",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "the next several years",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "years",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "at least the next 20 years",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "second",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "10-year",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "10- year",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Fair Value",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "DriversSeth Goldstein",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "CFA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "23",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "250",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "9",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "1.79 million",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2024",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "half",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Model Y",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        },
        {
          "text": "the beginning of the year",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar 2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar, Inc.",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar Research Services",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "LLC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "6",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar Equity Analyst Report Report",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "17",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "00:55",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC Reporting Currency",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "USD Exchange",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "keywords": [
        "Fair Value and Profit DriversSeth Goldstein",
        "the same period",
        "Jun",
        "The information",
        "NASDAQ - ALL",
        "USD Exchange",
        "Tesla's cost",
        "BEV production",
        "excess returns",
        "informational purposes"
      ],
      "summary": "Tesla Inc TSLA QQ 16 Jul 2025 21:42, UTC Last Price Fair Value Estimate PriceFVE Market Cap Economic MoatTM Equity Style Box Uncertainty Capital Allocation ESG Risk Rating Assessment1 321.67 USD 250.00 USD 1.29 1.04 USD Tril Narrow 3 Large Growth Very High Exemplary ;;;;; 16 Jul 2025 30 Jan 2025 05:50, UTC 16 Jul 2025 4 Jun 2025 05:00, UTC line with its peers, we think Tesla will be able to maintain its proprietary technological advantage."
    },
    {
      "text": "Tesla Inc TSLA QQ 16 Jul 2025 21:42, UTC Last Price Fair Value Estimate PriceFVE Market Cap Economic MoatTM Equity Style Box Uncertainty Capital Allocation ESG Risk Rating Assessment1 321.67 USD 250.00 USD 1.29 1.04 USD Tril Narrow 3 Large Growth Very High Exemplary ;;;;; 16 Jul 2025 30 Jan 2025 05:50, UTC 16 Jul 2025 4 Jun 2025 05:00, UTC launched by midyear. As the company is ramping up production of the new vehicles, we expect automotive gross margins excluding credits will remain in the mid-teens, below management's long- term goal of 20. Longer term, we assume Tesla delivers 4.3 million vehicles per year in 2030. Our forecast is well below management's aspirational goal of selling 20 million vehicles by the end of this decade. However, it is a more than double the 1.8 million vehicles delivered in 2024. Our forecast assumes Tesla slightly lower Model 3 and Model Y deliveries and ramps up volume of the Cybertruck to around 50,000 deliveries per year, far below management's goal of 250,000. We forecast Tesla will launch its affordable SUV priced in the mid-30,000 range with some deliveries coming in 2025 and a ramp-up in 2026 at a pace similar to the Model 3 ramp-up in 2018, the first full year the vehicle was sold. We think deliveries of the affordable SUV will exceed those of the Model Y and Model 3, as the lower price point of this vehicle should attract a larger consumer base. We think Tesla will be successful in continuing to reduce its manufacturing costs on a per vehicle basis. We forecast segment gross margin will recover to the low 20s by the end of the decade, above the 19 generated in 2023 but below the 29 achieved in 2022. We assume revenue growth and margin expansion from autonomous software sold on a subscription basis. We also assume the successful growth of the insurance business and increased profits from the charging business result in long-term profit growth and margin expansion in the services and other segment. In energy generation and storage, we assume the business averages annual revenue growth at roughly a 30 range during our 10-year forecast, primarily driven by accelerating demand for energy storage systems. While we forecast ESS prices to decline, the fall will largely be driven by cheaper battery costs, which should not affect profitability. As volume grows, unit costs should fall. Combined with recurring revenue from long-term power purchase agreements and AI trading software, we expect the business will turn profitable and generate gross margins in line with peers such as Enphase and SolarEdge. We assume overhead expenses continue to decline as a percentage of sales as the company benefits from operating leverage as deliveries grow. As a result, we forecast companywide operating margin will return to the midteens by the end of the decade, in line with the 17 achieved in 2022 and well above the 9 in 2023. To fund this growth, we assume Tesla will have around 115 billion in capital expenditures over the next decade. Our base case also adds the present value of Tesla's robotaxi business, Dojo's AI training services, and Morningstar 2025. All Rights Reserved. Unless otherwise provided in a separate agreement, you may use this report only in the country in which its original distributor is based. The information, data, analyses and ?(cid:0) opinions presented herein do not constitute investment advice; are provided solely for informational purposes and therefore are not an offer to buy or sell a security; and are not warranted to be correct, complete or accurate. The opinions expressed are as of the date written and are subject to change without notice. Except as otherwise required by law, Morningstar shall not be responsible for any trading decisions, damages or other losses resulting from, or related to, the information, data, analyses or opinions or their use. The information contained herein is the proprietary property of Morningstar and may not be reproduced, in whole or in part, or used in any manner, without the prior written consent of Morningstar. Investment research is produced and issued by subsidiaries of Morningstar, Inc. including, but not limited to, Morningstar Research Services LLC, registered with and governed by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. To order reprints, call 1 . To license the research, call 1 . Please see important disclosures at the end of this report. Page 7 Morningstar Equity Analyst Report Report as of 17 Jul 2025 00:55, UTC Reporting Currency: USD Trading Currency: USD Exchange: NASDAQ - ALL MARKETS",
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Tesla Inc",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "321.67 USD 250.00 USD",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "30 Jan 2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025 4",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "05:00",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "midyear",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "20",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "4.3 million",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2030",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "20 million",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "the end of this decade",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "1.8 million",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2024",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Model 3",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        },
        {
          "text": "Cybertruck",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "around 50,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "250,000",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2026",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Model 3",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        },
        {
          "text": "2018",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "the first full year",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Model 3",
          "label": "PRODUCT"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "20s",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "the end of the decade",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "19",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2023",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "29",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "annual",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "roughly a 30",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "10-year",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "AI",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Enphase",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "SolarEdge",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "the end of the decade",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "17",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "9",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2023",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "around 115 billion",
          "label": "MONEY"
        },
        {
          "text": "the next decade",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Dojo",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar 2025",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar, Inc.",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar Research Services",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "LLC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Page 7",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar Equity Analyst Report Report",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "17",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "00:55",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC Reporting Currency",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "USD Exchange",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "keywords": [
        "peers",
        "the new vehicles",
        "its affordable SUV",
        "those",
        "Model",
        "roughly a 30 range",
        "The information",
        "Jun",
        "NASDAQ - ALL",
        "autonomous software"
      ],
      "summary": "Tesla Inc TSLA QQ 16 Jul 2025 21:42, UTC Last Price Fair Value Estimate PriceFVE Market Cap Economic MoatTM Equity Style Box Uncertainty Capital Allocation ESG Risk Rating Assessment1 321.67 USD 250.00 USD 1.29 1.04 USD Tril Narrow 3 Large Growth Very High Exemplary ;;;;; 16 Jul 2025 30 Jan 2025 05:50, UTC 16 Jul 2025 4 Jun 2025 05:00, UTC launched by midyear."
    },
    {
      "text": "Tesla Inc TSLA QQ 16 Jul 2025 21:42, UTC Last Price Fair Value Estimate PriceFVE Market Cap Economic MoatTM Equity Style Box Uncertainty Capital Allocation ESG Risk Rating Assessment1 321.67 USD 250.00 USD 1.29 1.04 USD Tril Narrow 3 Large Growth Very High Exemplary ;;;;; 16 Jul 2025 30 Jan 2025 05:50, UTC 16 Jul 2025 4 Jun 2025 05:00, UTC the Optimus humanoid robot sales. We expect robotaxis will enter the ride-hailing market by 2028 and rollout on a city-by-city basis, similar to how Waymo, Uber, and Lyft increased their service locations. Tesla will take an asset-light approach, selling vehicles and then running the software. Our robotaxi valuation account for around 65 per share, or a little more than 20, of our Tesla valuation. Our FSD software subscription valuation accounts for 25 per share, or around 10 of our fair value estimate. Optimus and Dojo combine for roughly 25 per share, an additional 10 of our fair value estimate. Given the wide range of outcomes, we also model upside and downside scenarios. Our upside scenario fair value estimate is 600. In this scenario, we assume Tesla delivers a little over 5 million vehicles per year by 2030 and the company benefits from cost reductions in excess of our base- case forecast. We also value robotaxi at around 175 per share, Optimus and Dojo at a combined 185 per share, and FSD software subscriptions at around 55 per share. Our downside scenario fair value estimate is 100 per share. In a downside scenario, we assume Tesla delivers less than 3.5 million vehicles in 2030. We also assume cost reductions do not materialize as planned and Tesla is forced to cut prices amid increasing competition. This keeps gross margin in the high teens, in line with the 19 generated in 2023. We also assume no economic benefit from autonomous driving software and sees slower growth in the insurance business. We assign no value to the company's ancillary businesses including robotaxis, Dojo's AI training services, and humanoid robots. Risk and UncertaintySeth Goldstein, CFA, Senior Equity Analyst, 23 Apr 2025 We assign Tesla a Very High Morningstar Uncertainty Rating as we see a wide range of potential outcomes for the company. The automotive market is highly cyclical and subject to sharp demand declines based on economic conditions. As an EV market leader, Tesla is subject to growing competition from traditional automakers and new entrants. As new lower-priced EVs enter the market, Tesla may be forced to continue to cut prices, reducing the firm's industry-leading profits. With more EV choices, consumers may view Tesla less favorably. The company is also investing heavily in RD to develop autonomous driving software, robotaxis, and humanoid robots with no guarantee these investments will bear fruit. As of the last SEC filing, Tesla's CEO owns roughly 12 of the company's stock and uses it as collateral for personal loans, which raises the risk of a large sale to repay debt. Tesla also faces political risk related to the political activities of CEO Elon Musk. Musk serves as an advisor to US President Donald Trump and campaigned for the far-right Alternative for Germany party. These activities risk turning away some consumers from buying a Tesla. Tesla faces ESG risks. As an automaker, Tesla is subject to potential product defects that could result in Morningstar 2025. All Rights Reserved. Unless otherwise provided in a separate agreement, you may use this report only in the country in which its original distributor is based. The information, data, analyses and ?(cid:0) opinions presented herein do not constitute investment advice; are provided solely for informational purposes and therefore are not an offer to buy or sell a security; and are not warranted to be correct, complete or accurate. The opinions expressed are as of the date written and are subject to change without notice. Except as otherwise required by law, Morningstar shall not be responsible for any trading decisions, damages or other losses resulting from, or related to, the information, data, analyses or opinions or their use. The information contained herein is the proprietary property of Morningstar and may not be reproduced, in whole or in part, or used in any manner, without the prior written consent of Morningstar. Investment research is produced and issued by subsidiaries of Morningstar, Inc. including, but not limited to, Morningstar Research Services LLC, registered with and governed by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. To order reprints, call 1 . To license the research, call 1 . Please see important disclosures at the end of this report. Page 8 Morningstar Equity Analyst Report Report as of 17 Jul 2025 00:55, UTC Reporting Currency: USD Trading Currency: USD Exchange: NASDAQ - ALL MARKETS",
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Tesla Inc",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "321.67 USD 250.00 USD",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "30 Jan 2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025 4",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "05:00",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Optimus",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "2028",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Waymo",
          "label": "WORK_OF_ART"
        },
        {
          "text": "around 65",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "a little more than 20",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "FSD",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "25",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "around 10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Optimus",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Dojo",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "roughly 25",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "an additional 10",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "600",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "a little over 5 million",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "2030",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "around 175",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Optimus",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Dojo",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "185",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "FSD",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "100",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "less than 3.5 million",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2030",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "19",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2023",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Dojo",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "UncertaintySeth Goldstein",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "CFA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "23",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "EV",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "EV",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "RD",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "SEC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "roughly 12",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Elon Musk",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Donald Trump",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Germany",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "NORP"
        },
        {
          "text": "ESG",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar 2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar, Inc.",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar Research Services",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "LLC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "8",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar Equity",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "17",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "00:55",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC Reporting Currency",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "USD Exchange",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "keywords": [
        "US President Donald Trump",
        "this scenario",
        "less than 3.5 million vehicles",
        "humanoid robots",
        "The information",
        "Jun",
        "NASDAQ - ALL",
        "USD Exchange",
        "informational purposes",
        "personal loans"
      ],
      "summary": "Tesla Inc TSLA QQ 16 Jul 2025 21:42, UTC Last Price Fair Value Estimate PriceFVE Market Cap Economic MoatTM Equity Style Box Uncertainty Capital Allocation ESG Risk Rating Assessment1 321.67 USD 250.00 USD 1.29 1.04 USD Tril Narrow 3 Large Growth Very High Exemplary ;;;;; 16 Jul 2025 30 Jan 2025 05:50, UTC 16 Jul 2025 4 Jun 2025 05:00, UTC the Optimus humanoid robot sales."
    },
    {
      "text": "Tesla Inc TSLA QQ 16 Jul 2025 21:42, UTC Last Price Fair Value Estimate PriceFVE Market Cap Economic MoatTM Equity Style Box Uncertainty Capital Allocation ESG Risk Rating Assessment1 321.67 USD 250.00 USD 1.29 1.04 USD Tril Narrow 3 Large Growth Very High Exemplary ;;;;; 16 Jul 2025 30 Jan 2025 05:50, UTC 16 Jul 2025 4 Jun 2025 05:00, UTC recalls, including its autonomous driving software. We see a moderate impact should this occur. Another risk involves employee retention. If Tesla is unable to retain key employees, such as CEO Elon Musk, its image as an innovative company could decline. We see a low probability but moderate materiality. Additional ESG risks include potential patent litigation as the company relies on new technology to improve its EVs and energy storage systems. We see a low probability but moderate materiality should this occur. Tesla may also face regulatory issues in some US states due to laws that require automakers and dealers to be separate. We see a moderate probability but low materiality. Capital AllocationSeth Goldstein, CFA, Senior Equity Analyst, 11 Mar 2025 We award Tesla an Exemplary Capital Allocation Rating based on our framework that assesses its balance sheet, investment decisions, and shareholder distributions. We rate the balance sheet as sound. Tesla's revenue is subject to high cyclicality, and the majority of the company's debt and financial lease obligations are due within the next three years. However, with a healthy balance sheet and cash far exceeding total debt, Tesla should be able to easily meet its financial obligations. We view management's investments as exceptional. Tesla's aspiration is to increase its EV volume from a little under 1.8 million vehicles in 2024 to 20 million by 2030. To do so, the company built new factories around the world, including in China, the EU, and US. Given strong consumer demand, we think the capacity expansion plans make sense. We are also in favor of the company's focus on reducing its manufacturing costs on a per unit basis while investing to maintain its technological advantage. To reduce costs, Tesla makes its own batteries, with plans to increase its own battery cell production from an annual capacity of 100 gigawatt-hours in 2022 to 3 terawatt-hours by 2030. The battery will also be incorporated into the structural design of the EV. Tesla's battery improvements aim to reduce cost on a per kWh basis, increase range, and reduce investment on a per GWh basis. We are in favor of the focus on reducing costs, as this should enable Tesla to keep its cost advantage intact as large legacy automakers electrify further this decade. Reduced manufacturing costs should enable Tesla to increase profit margins for its existing vehicles and produce an affordable sedan and SUV in the future at a profitable level. We also think management is smart to look at adding ancillary revenue streams such as autonomous driving software, which can be a product differentiator if Tesla is successful, as well as selling insurance. We are in favor of the move to open Tesla's charging network to non-Tesla vehicles as it can drive additional revenue and profits from charging stations by increasing the capacity utilization of each station. We see shareholder distributions as appropriate. Tesla does not pay a dividend and to date has not repurchased shares. Instead, it has used the capital markets to issue stock, most recently at value- accretive levels. Given that Tesla is investing heavily in expanding its vehicle and battery production Morningstar 2025. All Rights Reserved. Unless otherwise provided in a separate agreement, you may use this report only in the country in which its original distributor is based. The information, data, analyses and ?(cid:0) opinions presented herein do not constitute investment advice; are provided solely for informational purposes and therefore are not an offer to buy or sell a security; and are not warranted to be correct, complete or accurate. The opinions expressed are as of the date written and are subject to change without notice. Except as otherwise required by law, Morningstar shall not be responsible for any trading decisions, damages or other losses resulting from, or related to, the information, data, analyses or opinions or their use. The information contained herein is the proprietary property of Morningstar and may not be reproduced, in whole or in part, or used in any manner, without the prior written consent of Morningstar. Investment research is produced and issued by subsidiaries of Morningstar, Inc. including, but not limited to, Morningstar Research Services LLC, registered with and governed by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. To order reprints, call 1 . To license the research, call 1 . Please see important disclosures at the end of this report. Page 9 Morningstar Equity Analyst Report Report as of 17 Jul 2025 00:55, UTC Reporting Currency: USD Trading Currency: USD Exchange: NASDAQ - ALL MARKETS",
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Tesla Inc",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "321.67 USD 250.00 USD",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "30 Jan 2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025 4",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "05:00",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Elon Musk",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Capital AllocationSeth Goldstein",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "CFA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "11",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Exemplary Capital Allocation Rating",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "the next three years",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "EV",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "a little under 1.8 million",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2024",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "20 million",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2030",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "China",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "EU",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "US",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "annual",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "100",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "3",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2030",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "EV",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "this decade",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar 2025",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar, Inc.",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar Research Services",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "LLC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "1",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "9",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "Morningstar Equity Analyst Report Report",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "17",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "00:55",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC Reporting Currency",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "USD Exchange",
          "label": "ORG"
        }
      ],
      "keywords": [
        "cash",
        "the capacity utilization",
        "Reduced manufacturing costs",
        "The information",
        "Jun",
        "NASDAQ - ALL",
        "a low probability",
        "USD Exchange",
        "informational purposes",
        "a healthy balance sheet"
      ],
      "summary": "Tesla Inc TSLA QQ 16 Jul 2025 21:42, UTC Last Price Fair Value Estimate PriceFVE Market Cap Economic MoatTM Equity Style Box Uncertainty Capital Allocation ESG Risk Rating Assessment1 321.67 USD 250.00 USD 1.29 1.04 USD Tril Narrow 3 Large Growth Very High Exemplary ;;;;; 16 Jul 2025 30 Jan 2025 05:50, UTC 16 Jul 2025 4 Jun 2025 05:00, UTC recalls, including its autonomous driving software."
    },
    {
      "text": "Tesla Inc TSLA QQ 16 Jul 2025 21:42, UTC Last Price Fair Value Estimate PriceFVE Market Cap Economic MoatTM Equity Style Box Uncertainty Capital Allocation ESG Risk Rating Assessment1 321.67 USD 250.00 USD 1.29 1.04 USD Tril Narrow 3 Large Growth Very High Exemplary ;;;;; 16 Jul 2025 30 Jan 2025 05:50, UTC 16 Jul 2025 4 Jun 2025 05:00, UTC capacity, we think the best use of capital is internal reinvestment to fund organic growth rather than shareholder distribution. However, with solid free cash flow generation and little debt, management said it may consider share repurchases in the future. Tesla is currently preparing to begin selling an affordable vehicle and building the required plants to ramp up production. Once this is complete and the initial factories are ramped up, we think share repurchases, at least to offset dilution from stock- based compensation, would make sense with excess cash flow. Elon Musk has been Tesla's CEO since 2008. Before co-founding Tesla, he co-founded and sold the internet payment system PayPal. Musk also co-founded SpaceX, Neuralink, and The Boring Co. Further, Musk purchased Twitter, now called X, in late 2022 and was CEO until mid-2023. For Tesla, Musk's compensation comes entirely from stock awards. Under the plan created in 2018, Musk earned 304 million stock option awards (split-adjusted, at a price of 23.34 per share) in 12 tranches based on meeting revenue, EBITDA, and market capitalization targets, which was completed by the end of 2022. This compensation package was voided by a Delaware judge following a shareholder lawsuit, though Tesla may appeal the ruling. For future compensation awards, while we understand the revenue and EBITDA targets for a growing company, we would prefer a return on invested capital metric be added. Analyst Notes Archive Tesla: Second-Quarter Deliveries Decline Confirms Our View for Lower 2025 Deliveries Seth Goldstein, CFA,Senior Equity Analyst,2 Jul 2025 Tesla reported second-quarter deliveries of 384,122 vehicles, a 13 decline versus the second quarter of 2024. Tesla shares were up 5 in premarket trading on the news. Why it matters: A second straight quarter of declining year-over-year deliveries is in line with our forecast for deliveries to decline in 2025. Through the first half of the year, Tesla's deliveries were down 13. The result also supports our view that Tesla's current product lineup is at market saturation. We don't think Tesla will see meaningful deliveries growth without a new lower-cost vehicle aimed at the affordable market. The bottom line: We maintain our 250 fair value estimate for narrow-moat Tesla. We view shares as overvalued with the stock trading in 2-star territory. In our view, Tesla's stock continues to reflect optimism for the rollout of the company's robotaxi business and prices in a successful full product launch next year, in line with management's guidance. We agree that robotaxi deserves a higher valuation than new vehicle launches. In our model, we value the robotaxi business higher than the valuation from new vehicle launches. Coming up: Tesla plans to release its earnings on July 23. We hope to hear an update on robotaxi testing and the exact steps to a full launch. We also hope to hear an update on the new affordable vehicle, which management said would launch this year. The robotaxi is in testing, but we view safety precautions, including employees riding in the vehicles, the geofenced testing area, and invite-only access as signs Tesla is still in the early stages. This supports our view that Tesla won't see a full robotaxi launch until 2028. We define a full robotaxi launch as when anyone in the Austin, Texas, Morningstar 2025. All Rights Reserved. Unless otherwise provided in a separate agreement, you may use this report only in the country in which its original distributor is based. The information, data, analyses and ?(cid:0) opinions presented herein do not constitute investment advice; are provided solely for informational purposes and therefore are not an offer to buy or sell a security; and are not warranted to be correct, complete or accurate. The opinions expressed are as of the date written and are subject to change without notice. Except as otherwise required by law, Morningstar shall not be responsible for any trading decisions, damages or other losses resulting from, or related to, the information, data, analyses or opinions or their use. The information contained herein is the proprietary property of Morningstar and may not be reproduced, in whole or in part, or used in any manner, without the prior written consent of Morningstar. Investment research is produced and issued by subsidiaries of Morningstar, Inc. including, but not limited to, Morningstar Research Services LLC, registered with and governed by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. To order reprints, call 1 . To license the research, call 1 . Please see important disclosures at the end of this report. Page 10 Morningstar Equity Analyst Report Report as of 17 Jul 2025 00:55, UTC Reporting Currency: USD Trading Currency: USD Exchange: NASDAQ - ALL MARKETS",
      "entities": [
        {
          "text": "Tesla Inc",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "321.67 USD 250.00 USD",
          "label": "QUANTITY"
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "30 Jan 2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "16",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025 4",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "05:00",
          "label": "TIME"
        },
        {
          "text": "UTC",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Elon Musk",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "2008",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "PayPal",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Neuralink",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "The Boring Co.",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Musk",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Twitter",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "late 2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "mid-2023",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "Musk",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "2018",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "304 million",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "23.34",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "12",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "the end of 2022",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Delaware",
          "label": "GPE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Tesla",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "Second-Quarter",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "Seth Goldstein",
          "label": "PERSON"
        },
        {
          "text": "CFA",
          "label": "ORG"
        },
        {
          "text": "second-quarter",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "384,122",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "13",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "the second quarter of 2024",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "5",
          "label": "CARDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "second",
          "label": "ORDINAL"
        },
        {
          "text": "2025",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
          "text": "the first half of the year",
          "label": "DATE"
        },
        {
